DIANE NGUYEN WEB DEVELOPER

(269) 384-9248 ■ d5nguyen@gmail.com
www.github.com/d5nguyen
www.linkedin.com/in/d5nguyen

SUMMARY

From teaching myself calculus in 12th grade to programming websites from scratch, being self-taught has been an essential part of who I am. As an educator I've also learned to absorb new ideas quickly, work collaboratively, and communicate effectively. These skills, along with an eye for clean and striking design and UX focus have served me well as I transition from teaching to developing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

- Responsive Web Design
- JQuery
- Django/Python
- Github/Git
- Photo editing/Photoshop
- Print design

PROJECTS

d5nguyen.github.io/PortfolioPage/

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

- Django Girls co-organizer, social media manager & print designer Pyladies event co-organizer
- Ladies that UX member
- GR Web Development member
- theProject team app building
- Bar Camp 2018 2 day event
- Beer City Code 2018 volunteer
- Hacktoberfest 2018
- Weekend For Good 2018 volunteer

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lighthouse Academy School - High School Paraprofessional and Substitute Teacher 2014-Present | Grand Rapids, MI

FACILITATE LEARNING and POSITIVE BEHAVIORAL and SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT OF VULNERABLE STUDENT POPULATIONS

- Staff of the Month September 2018
- Lead school district paraprofessionals to assemble job specific training manual
- Cite issues and collaboratively implement strategies for academic and behavioral interventions, resulting in steep decrease of recurring incidents
- Create accountability system leading to acceleration of student academic success on weekly basis
- Long-term substitute art teacher across all grades: elementary through high school
- Illustrate and design school store currency and posters using Photoshop & Gimp

Pfizer/Aerotek - Library Documentation Technician 2012-2014 | Kalamazoo, MI

COORDINATED WITH ONSITE and INTERNATIONAL CROSS-FUNCTIONAL TEAMS TO IDENTIFY and PREPARE MATERIALS UNDER TIME RESTRAINTS

- Streamlined procedures for processing incoming documentation that improved accuracy and workflow resulting in an 15% increase in productivity
- Built a reputation for having the quickest response and turn-around time for identifying and culling relevant materials during company-wide audits
- Reviewed and identified entry errors/follow protocol assuring accurate electronic documentation

Walgreens Pharmacy - Certified Pharmacy Technician 2009-2012 | Kalamazoo, MI

LEVERAGED MULTITASKING SKILLS TO PROVIDE CUSTOMER SERVICE TO 250+ WEEKLY CLIENTS WITH DIVERSE SOCIO-ECONOMIC BACKGROUNDS

- Serve as a liaison between customers, medical providers, and billing and insurance companies to assure compliance and accessibility
- Accurate and expedient translating and transcribing prescriptions
- Adept problem solving and assessment of client needs resulting in highest number of monthly Prescription Savings Club sales

EDUCATION

Responsive Web Design Certification JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification (ongoing) FreeCodeCamp.org	2019
Build Responsive Real World Websites with HTML5 and CSS3 Udemy.com	2018
Bachelors of Science, Psychology; Chemistry, and Biology Medallion Scholarship - \$40,000 Lee Honors College Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo, MI	2010